Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 1622. Wolfgang, Wilhelm, Pfalz, count of, 1578-1653 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Serenissimus Princaps Wolfgangus Wilhalmus, D.G.Comas Palatinus Rheni/Dux Bavariae, luliaci, Cliviae Et./D.A.van Dyck Pinxit. Cum pr:Lvilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 297.a 16.9 cm.
  - 1623. Wolfgang, Wilhelm, Pfalz count of, 1578-1653 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Wolfgang Wilhelmus/Comas Palatinus Rheni, Utriusque/Bavariaa, Iuliae, Cliviaa at Montium Dun. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 12.3 x 7.0 cm. Badly trimmed. P. 2 pag. 244 from unidentified series.
  - 1624. Wolkanstein-Rodanegg, Georg Ulrich, count of, 17th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Gaorgius Ulricus/Comes a Wolckenstein. at Rodeneg, haeraditarius/Praefectus stabuli Imperialis Aulicus, /Serenissimae Domus Austriacae ad Deputationem/Francofurtensem et Tractatus Pacis Univarsalis/Legatus Plenipotentiarius etc./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit, Corn. Galle iunior sculpsit. 1649. Accassit Privilagium Caesareum, Cum pmivilagio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Diligam te Domina, Fortitudo mea." Engraving. 30.5 a 19.7 cm. Singer No. 34065/98423. No, 105 from unidentified edition of Hulla A.van,Paciflcatoras orbis Christiani.
  - 1625. Wolleb, [Wolleben], Johann, 1586-1629 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Johannes Wollebius Theolog.Doct. Acade. Basilien:Profess: Ord. at Protemp.Ractor/ Aet.44 Obiit, Ao.l629, Qui sancta solus bene-vivit dicaris atqua/Praastus: aetarnum sic Bona-Vita tibi/Heim F. d.2. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left. Engraving. 14.5 a 10.4 cm.
  - 1626. Wolsay, Thomas, cardinal, abp. of York, chancellor of England, 1475-1530 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Thomas Wolseus Cardimalis. /Archiepiscopus Eboracensis/Angliaa Cancellarius etc. IF Fourdriniar sculp. Standing left profile in oblong. Engraving. 28.2 x 17.4 cm, Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1627. Wolsey, Thomas, cardinal, abp. of York, chancellor of England, 1475-1530 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Thomas Wolsey Arch-Bishop of Yorka,/~hanca1lour of England. Cardinal and Legate Ca/ Latere. He died at Leicastar Abby Anno Dni. 1529./the 29th of Novamber./W.M.sculp. Left profile in oblong. Stipple-engraving. Printed on verso of a teat fragment. 13.2 a 11.0 cm. No plate-mark.
  - 1628. Wolsey, Thomas, cardinal, abp. of York, chancellor of England, 1475-1530 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Cardinal/Wolsey./J.Houbraken sculp./In the possession of Mr.Kingsley. Impensis I. & P.Knapton, Londini, 1738. Left profile in oval. Ornamental background with bishop's tiara, cardinal's hat, crosier, snake book etc. Engraving. 37.5 x 22.8 cm. Singer No. 34080/98459. From: Thomas Birch, The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persams pf~ Great Britain, London, 1756.
  - 1629. Worlidge, Thomas, 1700-1766 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Tho. Worlidge./Fecit 1754. Half-portrait in studio looking left in oblong. Etching. 19.5 x 15.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1630. Worlidge, Thomas, 1700-1766 (Flat-box 12, Folder 19)
    Thomas Worlidge./Seipse pinxit. T.Chambars Scuip. Half-portrait in studio looking left in oblong. Engraving. 17.3 x 13.3 cm
  - 1631. Wotton, Sir Henry, 1568-1639 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Sir Henry Wottom./From the original of Cornelius Jansen in the/Bodleian Gallery,Oxford. /Drawn by H.Craasa & Engraved (with Permission) by T.Cheesman./London. Published Fab.y 1.1816 by Lackington, Allen & Co.and Longman, Hurst, Reas, Orme & Brown./Proof. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 37.2 x 25.0 cm. No plate-mark.
  - 1632. Wouters, Frans, 1612-1659 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Francis Woutars. /Fr.Wouters pinx. A.Bannerman Sculp. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 18.3 x 14.0 cm.
  - 1633. Wouters, Frans, 1612-1659 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
  - 1634. Wouwer [Waverius], Jan van den, 1574-1635 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Dominus Joannes Vanden Wouwer/Eq.Toparch Quaenastaa Regi Catholico Belli, et/Supre~ Aerarii in Belgio a Consilius./Amton. van Dyck pinxit. Paul Pomtius sculpsit. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Etching. 23.1 x 15.4 cm, Singer No. 34130/98559. Dutuit No. 23.7e. Mauquoy-H. No. 18. VIII. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1635. Wouwer [Waverius], Jan van den, 1574-1635
  - 1636. Wren, Sir Christopher, 1632-1723 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Sr Christopher Wren,/Sr G.Kneller pinx. A.Bannerman Sculp./Hugh Howard Esq. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Another anonymous portrait in oval tilted diagomally in lower left corner. Engraving. 18.4 x 13.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. From: Walpole, Horace Earl of Orford, Anecdotes of Painting in England, London, 1782.
  - 1637. Wren, Sir Christopher, 1632-1723 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
  - 1638. Wuijtiers, Jan Banning, 1619-1647 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Rdus.Dominus Joannes Banning Wuijtiers, Amstelredamensis, Natus a Christi 1591 Comaecratus Sacerdos Ao.l6l9. Obiit Ao. 1647. IHS/T.Matham fecit. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Eulogy of six lines under oval. Engraving. 30.0 x 19.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1639. Wyndham, Sir Wadham, 1610-1668 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    Sr William Windham Bart./From a Painting of Mr. Richardson belonging to the L,Bolinbroke./J.Houbraken sculps. Amst. 1741. Impensis I.& P. Knapton, Londini, 1741. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right, surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 37,5 a 20.6 cm. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 1640. Wykeham, William of, bishop of Winchester, 1323?-1404 (Flat-box 12, Folder 20)
    William of Wickham, Bishop of Winchester,! From a Picture at Winchester Collega./J. Houbrakan sculpsit Amst./Impensis J. & P.Knapton Londini 1738. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right in symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.5 x 23.5 cm. Singer No. 34239/98805. From: Birch, T. ,The Heads of The ~ Personsof Great Britain, J, Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 1641. Yelverton, Sir Christopher, 1535?-1612 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    Sir Christopher Yalverton Knight/of Gray's Inn./Justice of the King's Bench. Ammo Don. 1602. Aet. 66/From an Original Painting by/Janssen in the possession of the Publisher/London Published by S.Woodburg, 18l1./R.Dunkarton scuip. Bust in oblong looking left. Mezzotint. 15.9 x 10.7 cm.
  - 1642. Zieten, Hans Joachim von, 1699-1786 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    Zietan./Eduard Kretzschmar sc./Druck Geisacka & Davrient. Verlag von R.Wagner Berlin Menzal 1850. Equestrian knee-piece looking left.Photo-reproduction. 37.3 x 32.2 cm.
  - 1643. Zincke, Christian Friedrich, 1685-1767 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    Frederick Zincke,/J.Bretharton f. Bust in oblong looking left, Right profile of "Liotard' in oval at right lower corner. Engraving. 17.7 x 13.7 cm.
  - 1644. Zollikofar, Georg Joachim, 1730-1788 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    G.I.Zollkofar./Zu finden in Leipzig bai Bausa./A.Graff pinx.J.F.Bause sculps. 1778. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 27.0 x 19.6 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 34586/99622.
  - 1645. Zoust, Gerard, 18th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    Gerard Zoust./A.Bannerman Sculp. Bust in oblong looking left, On easel in left part of background portrait lettered: "Griffi~re". Second small portrait on scroll in right lower corner inscribed 'Edema". Engraving. 18.6 x 13.8 cm.
  - 1646. Zuccari [Zucchero], Frederico, 1540-1609 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    Fraderico Zuccharo ./A.Bannermam scuips. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 18.8 x 14.7 cm.
  - 1647. Zwingli, Ulrich, 1484-1531 (Flat-box 12, Folder 21)
    U.Zwingli./Gust.Zumpe sc.Zwickau B.D.Gebr.Schurnann. Right profile in octagon. Stipple-engraving. 18.8 x 12.6 cm.
- Series 2. Accn 2010-110, 2.0 Linear feet 208 items (prints)
  This subseries includes miscellanous prints/portraits not described in published catalogue by Lenkey.
  Per paperwork accompanying the prints:
  "Includes 19 prints by Albrecht Duerer the little passion, 18 copies, 1 large print by Lucas Van Leyden, 27 small prints, 8 prints depicting the apostles."
  - Misc. prints (7 prints) (Flat-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Misc. prints (14 prints) (Flat-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Misc. prints (12 prints) (Flat-box 13, Folder 3)
  - Misc. prints (Kolb gift 9/12/1978) (8 prints) (Flat-box 13, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified/Misc. prints (10 prints) (Flat-box 13, Folder 5)
  - Misc. small prints (15 prints) [1 of 3] (Flat-box 14, Folder 1)
  - Misc. small prints (14 prints) [2 of 3] (Flat-box 14, Folder 2)
  - Misc. small prints (20 prints) [3 of 3] (Flat-box 14, Folder 3)
  - Misc. small prints (14 prints) (Flat-box 14, Folder 4)
  - Misc. prints (33 prints) (Flat-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Emblems (24 prints) (Flat-box 15, Folders 1-2)
  - Misc. prints (29 prints) (Flat-box 15, Folders 3-4)
  - Apostles (8 prints) (Flat-box 15, Folder 5)